# Kellie Allen

# **Front End Developer**

#### Kellie Allen

Indianapolis, IN 46205

317.496.0565

kellierenee@gmail.com

Portfolio: <a href="https://kellieallen.github.io/">https://kellieallen.github.io/</a> Github: <a href="https://github.com/kellieallen">https://github.com/kellieallen</a>

Objective: Front end developer seeking team environment to continue to learn and grow my coding skills. Eight years experience on product side of Agile methodology, now working to take that day-to-day structure into a new position to design, learn, and grow as a developer.

### **Learned Skills**

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Agile, React, Angular 8, Postman, PostgreSQL, Material UI, Angular Material

#### Certifications

Certified Scrum Master (CSM)

• CSM certified since 2011. Served as both CSM and product owner in the Agile process.

# **Experience**

#### Cision / Product Manager, Visibility Reports

FEB 2019 - JULY 2019. NYC

Leveraged strong strategic and leadership insight directing the product roadmap for the company's news release distribution analytics platform while managing overall product development, launch, and maintenance of the Visibility Reports product.

#### Cision / Senior Manager of Global Reporting

JAN 2015 - FEB 2019, NYC

Worked directly with dev team to implement new features for Visibility Reports product. Taking feedback from internal and external stakeholders, I utilized Jira and the agile method to push the product forward.

#### PR Newswire / Manager of Business Intelligence

JAN 2008 - DEC 2014, NYC

Led MultiVu's reporting department, tasked with providing ROI reporting for both traditional broadcast and multimedia clients. I was a co-Product Owner in our Scrum Methodology for reporting software development, where I oversaw the launch of client and internal feature requests from conception to deployment.

I was also heavily involved in our social media efforts, running the Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest accounts.

#### **PR Newswire / Internet Reporting Assistant**

MAR 2006 - DEC 2007, NYC

Provided ROI Reporting for the launch of PR Newswire's Multimedia News Release. I created customized reports for clients showing the value of sharing their multimedia assets beyond the traditional press release.

# **Education**

# **Eleven Fifty Academy / Javascript Immersive**

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

# Girl Develop It / Intro to Python

2018

# **Indiana University** / Bachelor of Arts, Journalism

1998 - 2002

# **Projects**

# Buzzfeed Quiz API

https://buzzfeed-quiz-api-project.web.app/

 Utilized Node.js, HTML and CSS to create an app that taps into the Edamam API to recreate a Buzzfeed quiz

#### Full CRUD React App

https://poshable.herokuapp.com/

• Built server side with Node.js and client side with React to create a full CRUD inventory tracking app for online sellers.

#### Angular App

https://github.com/kellieallen/swAPIGroupProject

 Angular app uses Star Wars API to display results on Star Wars queries. Styled with Angular Material.

### Full CRUD Angular App

https://badgebrigade.herokuapp.com/

 Team project utilizing Angular 8, Node.js and PostgreSQL to build a full CRUD app to connect Eleven Fifty boot camp grads with employers. Styled with Angular Material, Bootstrap and custom CSS.